American Association of Industrial Editors (AAIE) Records
American Association of Industrial Editors (AAIE) Records
1939-1969
American Association of Industrial Editors.
2.0 linear ft.
The American Association of Industrial Editors (AAIE) Records contains meeting minutes, reports, photographs, and other printed materials created and compiled by the American Association of Industrial Editors through its years of operation, 1938-1970.
2750900
Biographical History
The American Association of Industrial Editors (AAIE) was formed in 1938 by a small group of industrial publication editors. Within the first year of their association's operation they had memebers from 17 states and were producing their own publications. In 1941 the AAIE joined the National Council of Industrial Editors Association (NCIEA), which later became the International Council of Industrial Editors (ICIE). However, in 1946 the AAIE withdrew from the LCIE as a result of organizational differences. In 1970 the AAIE would again join the LCIE and together they formed the International Association of Business Communicators (IABC). Several months after this merger several former members of the AAIE laid aside materials pertaining to the early years of the AAIE. These materials were gifted, in 1976, to Syracuse University's School of Public Communication. The University had worked closely with the AAIE throughout the 1950's and 1960's. These records were later moved to the University's Special Collections Research Center in 1980.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The American Association of Industrial Editors Records consists of correspondence, minutes and reports, printed material, and historical material.
Correspondence contains corporate and personal correspondences from 1939-1969.
Minutes and reports contains minutes of AAIE meetings and reports from the years 1939-1969.
Printed material contains issues of the AAIE newsletter, Editors Notebook, from 1939-1969 and general printed material from 1939-1967.
Historical materials consists of material specifically laid aside by the AAIE for preservation, from 1943-1963. This series contains photographs, newpaper clippings, and printed materials, including conference programs and the organization's constitution and bylaws.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged by alphabetically by type or topic, with the exception of historical material which is placed at the end of the collection. Within that, material is arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Journalism; American Association of Industrial Editors.; National Council of Industrial Editors Association.; International Council of Industrial Editors.; International Association of Business Communicators.; Advertising, Industrial.; Business enterprises -- United States -- History.; Business travel.; House organs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Corporation reports.; Minutes (administrative records); Newsletters.; Photographs.; Editors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Samuel V. Kennedy, 1980.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - General, 1939-1969; 10 folders (Box 1)
  - General, undated (Box 1)
- Minutes and reports
  - Minutes and reports, 1945-1954; 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Minutes and reports, 1954-1966; 13 folders (Box 2)
- Printed material
  - Editors Notebook, 1939-1943 (Box 2)
  - Editors Notebook, 1944-1969; 11 folders (Box 3)
  - General, 1946-1953 (Box 3)
  - General, 1954-1967; 4 folders (Box 4)
- Historical material
  - Correspondence, 1943-1960; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Printed material, general, 1941-1963; conference programs, annual reports, copies of constitution and bylaws, etc.; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Minutes and reports, 1940-1960; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Photographs, 1950s (Box 4)